Guide to the Nannie Mae Tilley papers, 1883-1948 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Nannie Mae Tilley papers 1883-1948 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Tilley, Nannie M. (Nannie Mae), 1898-
.5 Linear Feet Approx. 704 Items
Nannie Mae Tilley (1898-1988) was a historian and curator of the Manuscripts Deptartment of Duke University.
The Nannie Mae Tilley papers contain correspondence and other materials collected by Tilley concerning servicemen in World War II, the Bonsack family of Virginia, and tobacco cultivation and manufacturing in Virginia. The large group of letters from U.S. servicemen reveals attitudes about military service, U.S. participation in World War II, and about Duke University, where many of them had been students. Another group of letters is from the John E. Bonsack family, and concerns the Bonsack family genealogy, particularly James E. Bonsack, inventor of cigarette rolling machine, and Jacob Bonsack, grandfather of John E. Bonsack, who owned a woolen mill at Good Intent, Virginia. Further materials, chiefly photostats of reports from Richmond, Virginia, printed in the New York Journal of Commerce, concern the production and marketing of tobacco in Virginia and methods of handling leaf tobacco. Also included is James A. Bonsack's obituary from 1924.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Nannie Mae Tilley papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift after 1969.
Collection Overview
The Nannie Mae Tilley papers contain correspondence and other materials collected by Tilley concerning servicemen in World War II, the Bonsack family of Virginia, and tobacco cultivation and manufacturing in Virginia. The large group of letters from U.S. servicemen reveals attitudes about military service, U.S. participation in World War II, and about Duke University, where many of them had been students. Another group of letters is from the John E. Bonsack family, and concerns the Bonsack family genealogy, particularly James E. Bonsack, inventor of cigarette rolling machine, and Jacob Bonsack, grandfather of John E. Bonsack, who owned a woolen mill at Good Intent, Virginia.
Further materials, chiefly photostats of reports from Richmond, Virginia, printed in the New York Journal of Commerce, concern the production and marketing of tobacco in Virginia and methods of handling leaf tobacco. Also included is James A. Bonsack's obituary from 1924.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Bonsack, John E.
Bonsack family
Bonsack, Jacob, 1819-1889
Bonsack, James E.
Duke University -- Students
United States. Army -- Military life
Cigarette industry -- United States
Industries -- Virginia
Soldiers -- United States -- Correspondence
Tobacco -- Virginia
Tobacco industry -- Economic aspects -- United States
Tobacco industry -- North Carolina
Universities and colleges -- North Carolina -- Durham
Woolen and worsted manufacture -- Virginia
World War, 1939-1945 -- Personal narratives, American
Virginia -- Commerce
Virginia -- History
Contents of Collection
- Nannie Mae Tilley papers, 1883-1948 and undated, (2 boxes; 2 folders)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1944 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1948 and undated (Box 2)
  - Pope, Warren House Division (Box 2)
  - Shepard, Elizabeth Division (Box 2)
  - Atkins, Wade W. Division (Box 2)
  - Goodwin, Noma Lee Division (Box 2)
  - Clippings and printed materials: 1941-1945 and undated (Box 2)
  - Financial papers, 1943-1945 (Box 2)
  - Miscellany, 1942-1943 and undated (Box 2)
  - Addition to collection (Box Sec. A: 130)
  - Oversize items (Opaperfolder 1)